## **Eric Hendrickson**

San Diego, CA 92116 • (619) 942-3810 • hendrickson02@gmail.com github.com/hendrickson02 • linkedin.com/in/hendrickson02

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, XML,
  Java, C/C++, Bash scripting, Python, OCaml, Haskell, SPARC
- Testing: JUnit, RSpec, Capybara
- Experienced with Git, Qt Creator, and Android Studio
- Familiar with Windows 10, OS X, and Linux
- Have studied and utilized data structures and algorithms, as well as various design patterns, such as MVC and Prototype Pattern
- Familiar with development practices such as Waterfall, Agile, and Scrum
- Conversant in Mandarin Chinese and Spanish

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **HidIt** — Google Chrome Extension (github.com/hendricksono2/HidIt)

November 2016 - present

- Commissioned and paid for by a college student as a study aid
- Functionality comes from JavaScript and the jQuery DOM
- When a user clicks on a word, it becomes invisible, thus making any web page an interactive "flash card"
- If necessary, the user can also hover the mouse over the word to reveal the word, and upon clicking the word cause it to reappear as it was before it was clicked

### **Rent-It** — *Android App* (github.com/hendricksono2/CSE110W240T10)

January 2016 - March 2016

- App that my team in my Software Engineering course at UCSD created
- Seeks to blend concepts from eBay and Craigslist into a clean, convenient app for the purpose of renting items to others
- Written in Android Studio, used Firebase to manage our database. My role was mostly front end.
- Also utilized various design patterns taught in the course along with Agile and Scrum development practices
- User may create an account and login with username and password
- User may also post and delete listings

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Uber and Lyft** — Rideshare Driver

April 2016 - present

Works for these rideshare services within San Diego County

# **Yanbian University of Science and Technology,** Yanji, China — *English Conversation Teacher/Team Leader*

August 2011 - July 2013

- Taught English Conversation to Chinese, North Korean, and South Korean students
- Was team leader for my own course, which instructed students with no English language background
- Office responsibility was to manage the computers and software

#### **EDUCATION**

### **LEARN Academy,** San Diego — Ruby on Rails Stack Coding Bootcamp

November 2016 - present

Had instruction in the Ruby on Rails and JavaScript development stack and completed various projects using these skills

## **University of California San Diego**, San Diego — Extension Studies/Concurrent Enrollment

January 2014 - March 2016

Completed courses in topics such as Discrete Mathematics, Data Structures, Algorithms, Software Engineering, and others

## **San Diego Mesa College,** San Diego — Computer and Information Sciences

August 2013 - December 2013

Took courses in Java and C/C++

## **University of California San Diego**, San Diego — B.A. in Linguistics and B.A. in Chinese Studies

September 2006 - June 2011

- Double major in Linguistics with an emphasis in Cognition and Language Acquisition and interdisciplinary major of Chinese Studies
- Graduated cum laude with a 3.656 GPA and was awarded a Phi Beta Kappa Scholar.

#### **HOBBIES**

- Reading
- Studying history and [human] languages
- Making home brewed mead and beer

#### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

Because I lived in China for two years and even before that studied its language, history, and culture I am someone who can not only see multiple perspectives but can adapt to them and incorporate them into my own life. I believe that this experience will, when married with my programming skills and problem solving abilities, make me a valuable asset to whomever hires me and aid me in the creation of quality software.